<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-10T14:54:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">j-miskill.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Getting Rid of Social Media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/17/getting-rid-of-social-media.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Rid of Social Media" /><published>2024-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/04/17/getting-rid-of-social-media</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/17/getting-rid-of-social-media.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="getting-rid-of-social-media-was-the-best-thing-ive-done-in-a-while">Getting rid of social media was the best thing I’ve done in a while</h1>

<p>Over the past two or three years, I have gotten rid of most social media. I think it was the best thing that I’ve done 
in a long time. Let me tell you why.</p>

<h2 id="the-types">The types</h2>

<p>I never had TikTok. I never had Facebook (except to find certain businesses and groups). I have only ever really had
Snapchat and Instagram (and technically LinkedIn) if you count that. These are roughly the types of social that I have
had - and I think they are decently mainstream for the purposes of this article.</p>

<p>I also want to lump in two more. Two more that are probably quite surprising. Email and YouTube. In fact, go ahead and 
throw all the streaming services in there.</p>

<h2 id="what-happens-when-you-have-social-media">What happens when you have social media</h2>

<p>Dopamine. And the bad kind.</p>

<p>I don’t really know that much. However, I do know that dopamine is one of the best and worst chemicals that our bodies 
produce. I will compare us to much older human beings.</p>

<p>It is funnny to compare to time before the industrial and agricultural revolutions because
it seems so long ago. And, of course, I think that those times were largely worse than now. I completely agree with that. 
You would not catch me in the 1600s England. No, thank you, I’ll go ahead and pass. However, it makes sense to compare 
people from then with people today because of the stark differences.</p>

<p>Let’s keep it simple: I have read, and I believe, that dopamine is a motivation chemical. So, people from pre-industrial
and pre-agricultural revolutions got plenty of that chemical because their motivation was to stay alive and provide for 
their families. Now, we do not have to struggle to get food, water, and shelter. In fact, we do not have to struggle to 
live a life full of contentment. So our dopamine hits have changed.</p>

<p>Now, people receive these motivations from doing easy things. Looking at social media. Looking at email. Looking at YouTube. 
These are all things that people do that triggers dopamine. Then, it makes us want more and more and more.</p>

<h2 id="the-flip-side">The flip side</h2>

<p>Dopamine, as stated before, is the motivation chemical. We don’t only get it from social media. We get it from eating food.
We get it from working out (eventually). We get it from doing hard and difficult things (eventually).</p>

<p>Now, my free time looks like this: practicing music, fly-fishing, hanging out with friends, tying flies, etc. What I have
found is that the more I slow myself down from the feeling of, “oh gosh, I need to be doing something right now”, the more
I feel content and the more productive/strong/emotionally capable I feel. It is really just about that: slow down. I have
to tell myself this multiple times a day. But it truly helps.</p>

<h2 id="slowing-down">Slowing down</h2>

<p>I think we should all slow down a second. Even as I write this, I am actively telling myself to slow down. Sometimes,
I will start writing a sentence just for the sake of writing the sentence. I have it in my head that when I sit down to 
write, I need to be writing the whole time, which is incorrect. In reality, I just want to be true to myself.</p>

<p>Slowing down for me has allowed me at times to feel my true self. You know that feeling when it feels like you and the 
universe are vibrating at the exact same frequency? That feeling when you float in the ocean completely weightless to gravity? 
That is the feeling of slowing down.</p>

<p>This art of slowing down was born out of a desire to be more connected with the people around me at UVA. Being a fourth year,
I have felt that haven’t spent enough time with the people I care about. Which is upsetting. It is likely because when I was
a younger UVA student, I felt I needed to bounce from thing to thing, trying to keep my head above water. Now, I feel like
I am a strong swimmer, making it through calmly.</p>

<p>Recently I have been thinking about that feeling of resonating with the universe. We can all feel it as human beings and, 
moreover, we should all strive to feel it. This year, I feel I have made the most progress that I have ever made towards 
becoming my truest and best self. All of this is attributed to the art of slowing down.</p>

<p>I feel myself being the calm person. Resonating deeply with the world around me. Which involves being in nature quite a
bit. Which involves slowing myself down for other humans. Fly-fishing, mountain biking, hiking, surfing, cooking. These
are all things that make me feel that resonance deep within my soul. I am the one who can stay up until 3am talking, shooting
the shit only to be up the next morning ready to head deep into the heart of Shenandoah to fish. I will run 30 miles and 
get faster with each mile. I will have off days. I will have on days. I will help people with my whole self and nothing
less than that.</p>

<p>That is what you get with no social media. I feel dialed.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting rid of social media was the best thing I’ve done in a while]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/02/Introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2024-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/04/02/Introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/02/Introduction.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="hi-im-jackson">Hi, I’m Jackson!</h1>

<p>I am a fourth year at the University of Virginia studying computer science for my undergraduate and graduate degrees. In Fall 2024 I will officially be a masters student going for my MCS degree.</p>

<h3 id="my-interests">My Interests</h3>
<p>I am interested in creating software for the public good; when I land a job, I want to use that job to promote the public welfare and create better lives for those around the world. I believe that technology can be the answer to that.</p>

<p>Recently, I have found data science, specifically within the realms of artificial intelligence and machine learning to be fascinating. I think that these tools can be used to create lots of good in the world. One movement that I am absolutely enamored with is <a href="https://ai4sibook.org/">AI For Social Good</a>. I will likely be writing about lots of these things very soon.</p>

<p>In addition to all the computer science, I am double majoring in cognitive science. I find the study of the brain to be intrinsically very interesting. Lately, I have been reading and thinking about problem-solving, focus, and flow.</p>

<h3 id="why-did-i-create-this-website">Why Did I Create This Website</h3>

<p>WordPress sucks for free writing. I am not a professional looking to make money by writing crap all the time. I am looking for a place to be creative an express myself.</p>

<h3 id="contact">Contact</h3>

<p>I can be reached at <a href="jcm4bsq@virginia.edu">jcm4bsq@virginia.edu</a>. You can also reach out to me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jackson-miskill-291578213/">LinkedIn</a>, if you would like.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi, I’m Jackson!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coding Is Fun</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/12/Coding-Is-Fun.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding Is Fun" /><published>2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/12/Coding-Is-Fun</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/12/Coding-Is-Fun.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="coding-is-fun">Coding is Fun</h1>

<p>April 12, 2023</p>

<p>I am a UVa student, in the College of Arts and Science, and I decided to double major in Computer Science and Cognitive Science. When I graduate in May 2024, I will have one degree (a B.A.), but it will be in two disciplines. I don’t know if those disciplines will be written down for me on the degree or not.</p>

<p>Computer science is really fun. It’s insanely neat and such a crazy phenomenon that we as humans harnessed and created electricity and have been able model human-computers (olden days) with computational models like finite automaton and Turing Machines. It’s even more amazing that in reducing our cognitive load to simply 0s and 1s, we can implement nearly anything we can think of.</p>

<p>I am writing today about the reason I chose Computer Science, as a sort of a love letter to the major and the discipline, but also as a reminder to myself that I fell in love with this major for a reason.</p>

<p>My Journey
I chose Computer Science for one very simple reason: when I completed assignments, it made me feel good. When I first started out, I was a second year, taking Introduction to Programming (CS 1112). Every assignment was a small puzzle. There were little intricacies to it, little quirks and tools that you would have to use, and eventually, it would run! I found myself constantly entering flow states while coding.</p>

<p>Then, I took Data Structures and Algorithms as well as Discrete Mathematics (Spring second year). Things certainly took a turn here. The assignments were a lot more difficult. In DSA1, I was super confused at file structures and how I was supposed to write code that made senses structurally. One thing that UVa CS Professors don’t understand is that not everyone comes from a CS background. That coupled with the fact that assignments take a lengthy amount of time- so much that you don’t have time to practice, and it made sense why I struggled through that class. Nevertheless, I found it utterly fascinating and intriguing. Just the way that we could use code to more efficiently structure data so that we could use it better, then write instructions so that the data could be used better- it was awesome in my opinion. Discrete mathematics opened the door to the fact that things in CS were going to get a lot more difficult than weird file structures. We started talking about set theory, about proofs by contradiction and induction. This is when things got really tough. However, I still found it fascinating. I had yet to have a class in college where I was this “into” and engaged with the work I was doing. I loved it. It was at the end of this semester that I decided to major in Computer Science.</p>

<p>Advertisement
In the summer in between second and third year, I had an awesome opportunity to work in an undergraduate research experience program. I spent the summer working on a coding project that is still being developed and deployed today. It was a huge jump in my coding abilities.</p>

<p>My third year Fall was spent in Algorithms, in Computer Structure and Organization, and in Software Development Essentials. This is when things got a little sour. I overwhelmed myself. I didn’t know how difficult these courses would be, and I thought I could manage alright, but it was incredibly difficult. The sheer amount of work for each class was insane in itself. Additionally, coming from a non-CS background made things very difficult. I also overextended myself as far as commitments goes. I didn’t fail my classes by any means (Bs), but I felt as if I went from “fascination” to “scrambling to finish oh god please good grade”. It was sort of heartbreaking. Additionally, I felt like I never had the time to explore code and practice on my own- which I did in semesters previous just due to the fact that I understood things. In looking back on things, it was really just CSO1 that deadlocked me. The class was incredibly difficult, the TAs that I asked questions to did not help me, and I had no friends in the class. It was an absolute grind to get that B.</p>

<p>I am currently in discrete mathematics and theory 2, computer structure and organization 2, and human-computer interaction. These classes are ALL grinds. I enjoy them, but I still feel as if I am in scrambled eggs mode. I don’t want to be in scrambled eggs mode.</p>

<p>The Future With Code in it
I really do enjoy coding. I think that the ideal day would be a day where I could use code to build something really, really neat. I would love to be a part of an organization that uses code to fix environmental problems, build sustainable energy solutions, create cloud computing frameworks, build more software for computing purposes, and just in general does computer development for good purposes.</p>

<p>I don’t think I could ever work for any social media company. I just came to terms with the fact that YouTube is a social media. I don’t want to contribute to their code base.</p>

<p>6 months
In an ideal world, I would give myself 6 months to 1 year to figure myself out. I feel like I need some space to figure things out, to work on my own coding projects, and to just learn more about myself. College has been incredible for the social connections, but now I feel like I need to dig deep and go on a journey with myself to sharpen my skills and knowledge as a programmer, increase my level of confidence, and find out what it is I truly want to do with code. Thankfully, I believe the job market is here to stay for coders.</p>

<p>In school I feel like I go from project to project, assignment to assignment, test to test, without really being able to sit down and dive into the code, or give myself the space to breath and think through problems at hand. I want that. I want to be an engineer that uses code to develop solutions for real problems. I think it’s a fantastic way to do things.</p>

<p>The paradox
I love to code, but I don’t want to spend all of my time sitting behind a desk, typing away. This is sort of a simple thing, but basically I want to be able to get outside and take my time on things. I know most companies offer good things like getting outside, so I’m not entirely worried.</p>

<p>Now
This has me thinking about a lot of stuff in the future. I’m going to stop here because I’ve got some other things rolling around. Thank you and peace!</p>

<p>PS:
I saw an eagle recently.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coding is Fun]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/02/An-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Update" /><published>2023-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/02/An-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/02/An-Update.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="an-update">An Update</h1>
<p>jmiskill</p>

<p>April 2, 2023
Quick Thoughts:</p>

<p>It’s been quite a while. This semester has certainly been very, very crazy. I, unfortunately, feel like that is my fault. I never seem to make the time work in my favor during the semester.</p>

<p>Most of the time, I just end up bouncing from class to class, assignment to assignment, etc just to find out that the week has flown by. I should always have the time to write and to play music and to do things that I genuinely find fun, fulfilling, and a soul patch for myself. However, being a computer science student, I find it to be a bit difficult sometimes.</p>

<p>My problem is where I feel like I need to do “xyz” before I can do an assignment. I am a CS student that did not grow up coding (unlike many of my peers), so intrinsically, I feel like I need to read articles, do practice, and take notes before I can actually go about completing an assignment.</p>

<p>However, I know this is not the case. I just need to jump into the work and get it done. For whatever reason, this has been difficult. Maybe it’s because of COVID. Maybe it’s from the nearly 2 year break I took from math and heavy science courses. Don’t get me wrong, I am not doing horribly- I’m an A and B student within a top 10-30 (depending on the source) University in the United States. I have experience and absolutely love coding. However, I find that maybe it’s difficult some of the times. And maybe I spend my time in a way that exhausts me rather than energizes me.</p>

<p>I’ve done some reading on that recently. I think there is something to be said for doing work that energizes you and lifts you up rather than crushes you and you don’t look forward to. Here is what lifts me up:</p>

<p>Writing
Planning, Developing, Implementing, and Testing code (no matter what it does; I just find all of it intrinsically amazing).
Creating music (even if just small licks to play over top of old songs
Running (I think lifting is important, I just don’t get the same feelings that I get from running- the literal runners high).
Collaborating with a group to develop a project (something I’m doing in my Human-Computer Interaction class)
Socializing somehow- whether that’s by getting coffee, going for a walk, just getting on the phone, etc
Getting outside into nature (even if literally just sitting outside)
Going to talks and concerts (I find a ton of natural inspiration from live events- I always come home with new ideas and excitement).
Volunteering (I normally despise getting out there, but once I do, I love being there- especially if the weather is nice)
Listening to entire records
I’m sure this list goes on further, but I think I will stop there at 10 for now. I enjoyed making that list. If you read this, maybe you can do it too.</p>

<p>I am also going to write a list of 10 things I find absolutely draining that I do.</p>

<p>Spending the whole day in one spot doing work (I have gotten in the habit
Scheduling my day to the T. Every hour accounted for.
Planning for meetings
Required readings (I know, this is maybe not the best thing to find draining, but whatever)
Going to lectures that are so dry it brings me to tears
Logistical, quick things: financial aid forms, fraternity forms, UVa forms.
Social Media: this is kind of a big one. Social media is so quick and easy, but it’s been draining. The only thing I have is LinkedIn, but I still go on that a good amount (unconsciously, too). This sort of includes text and email. It stops my brain from functioning as it resorts back to some sort of caveman like state.
Video media: I spend way too much time on YouTube. It’s not draining as much as it blocks my flow of thought. Every time I watch, it takes me 30 minutes to get back on track.
Life hacking. I read and watch a lot about “how to …. better” (study, sleep, workout, etc). All of these are “life hacks”. It’s draining. The reason is because I try these things out for a week, two weeks, etc, and eventually give up and then it makes me feel bad about that.
Memorizing things for class for quizzes and tests. Yuck. I’m tired of that.
Anyways, those are some thoughts from recently. I have had a bunch of gigs for the band recently that have been super fun. It’s been a blast to play. I will put some pictures here now.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An Update jmiskill]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eating Frogs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/14/Eating-Frogs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eating Frogs" /><published>2023-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/14/Eating-Frogs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/14/Eating-Frogs.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="eating-frogs">Eating Frogs</h1>
<p>jmiskill</p>

<p>January 14, 2023
Eating Frogs is a phrase (apparently a very uncommon one) that simply means-</p>

<p>If you have necessary things you need to get done. Do them now. Eat The Frog and get it over with.</p>

<p>My mom was the one who taught me this phrase. It was when I was a teenager and started to have more responsibilities and things that I needed to get done and ask for when she taught it to me. Since then, it has become a sort of a life motto and internal rule that I follow without hesitation.</p>

<p>However, during college, frog eating has become significantly more difficult. The frogs are more complicated, they are bigger, some are unnecessary. Things are just different. I’m going to write about frogs today in hopes of having a good conversation with myself about my frogs.</p>

<p>Why Am I Writing About Eating Frogs
I had the idea to write about eating frogs on Monday when I sat down in the morning and wrote everything that I needed to get done that day. It was a giant list. On the list I had exactly this:</p>

<p>routine
Philanthropy Plans
Set Up New Phone
Clean Room
Call PT
Call Dominion
Text James
Fly fishing plan
Financial Plan
email UVa Career about internship money
Email Deloitte
Address and send letters
Plan next semester routine
Reach out to professors
Chores
Try on clothes
Next article idea generation
Darden
Make career center appointment
Handshake Response
Update UVa Info
I wanted to check off all of these things by the end of the day. At the end of that particular Monday, I had checked off 15 of the 21 things. Not so bad. Not perfect.</p>

<p>Advertisement</p>

<p>All of these items in my TODO part of my notebook are Frogs. Things we must conquer and “eat”. They are things that have to be done, require time, and are usually deemed unenjoyable.</p>

<p>The reason I am writing about this today is because I love Eating Frogs. If I can look back over a day at a list of things that I wanted to get done, and see a majority of checkmarks, that’s a good day. Furthermore, in a day and age where it is consistently more and more difficult to measure progress and feel accomplished, eating frogs provides a gateway to growth.</p>

<p>What Kind of Frogs Have I Eaten in the Past
There are a bunch of different kinds of frogs that exist out there. I have been able to classify frogs into one of two categories, each with a plethora of subcategories that I don’t have the time to write about individually. The two categories are “NEED” and “WANT”.</p>

<p>Before categorizing the previous example into the two categories, it is necessary to quickly explain my thoughts behind “NEED” and “WANT”. The “NEED” category are items that I absolutely have to take care of, for legal, health, or general “I have to take care of this in order to be a human being”. In the “WANT” category falls things that I have deemed are important to me that I want to do and take care of.</p>

<p>Monday’s Categorization:</p>

<p>NEED	BOTH	WANT
Set Up New Phone	Routine	Fly Fishing Plan
Clean Room	Philanthropy	reach out to professors
Call PT	plan next semester routine	Next article idea generation
Call Dominion	Darden	
Text James		
Financial Plan		
Email UVA about internship money		
Email Deloitte		
Address and send letters		
Chores		
Try on clothes		
Make career center appointment		
Handshake response		
Update UVA Info		
I tricked you. There are three categories.</p>

<p>As you can see, there were more things in the “NEED” category than the “WANT” category. However, you will find it interesting that there are a bunch of things that fall into the “BOTH” category.</p>

<p>Further, many of the things that fall into the “NEED” category are actually enjoyable to do. Cleaning my room, setting up the phone, and doing chores are three frogs I genuinely enjoyed eating (Have you gotten tired of me saying “eating frogs” yet?).</p>

<p>Not every single day looks like this for me. On the day of writing this article, I have only 6 frogs to eat. ( 😦 ). The point of this is that every day, each of the frogs adds up. Over time, I can count how many frogs I have eaten, and said that they were good for me in the long run. They helped me accomplish goals and set my mind straight.</p>

<p>One of the biggest challenges I have been focused on solving and thinking about as of late has been “make sense of the world around you”. It is a super broad and open-ended challenge. Finding a frog, eating it, and repeating is a fantastic system of achieving this. It takes a huge problem and condenses it down into it’s constituent parts. (this is a phenomenon I have been thinking about a lot and would like to explore more).</p>

<p>Over the course of this week, I have identified 48 frogs and eaten 26. I know that’s a pretty poor ratio, but it has pushed me along more than not doing this (I am starting to get a bad taste in my mouth from saying “eating frogs” so many times).</p>

<p>Resources about Eating Frogs
I personally think some of these resources are a little gross. Mainly because they are “productivity methods” and “time management” which I think can be really toxic and unhelpful. However, they are interesting to read if you would like to look through them.</p>

<p>Everything I have written up to this point has bee entirely from personal experience and my own thoughts.</p>

<p>Eat That Frog &amp; Start Accomplishing Your Goals | Brian Tracy
Frog rule: the key to productivity is tackling a tough task early in the day
What Is Eat the Frog? A Dead Simple System for Productivity Minimalists
Some Thoughts I Have About These Resources:
The first two articles talk about eating frogs as a work-specific thing. While this is true and useful, I use it for work, school, and personal life.
The articles talk about eating the biggest frog first. I think this is somewhat true. Life doesn’t always let me eat the biggest one first, though.
You can have a ton of frogs each day. That’s totally okay.
It’s okay to have days where you feel burnt and need to only eat a few frogs. I’m not always in the mood to eat frogs.
My Frog-Eating Strategy
I physically (not using the computer) write everything down.
I eat the biggest frog I can, first.
I am trying to create a routine of frogs I want and need to eat every day.
I physically cross things off my list.
I set different kinds of frogs.
I am trying to take time to reflect at the end of the day and the end of the week. I think forward progress is great and that eating frogs is a great way to try to cultivate meaning from a wildly unstructured life- but I want to analyze everything, too. Not only to see what I could do better, but also just to look back upon things.
Be present in the work.
Final Thoughts
There is a lot more to be said here. This is a sort of an ongoing conversation and process that I am having with myself. A lot of what was said here will mesh with one of the next articles I release about flow.</p>

<p>Further- this post has been relatively surface level about how I go about these things. Eating frogs has been on my mind, but has lead to a bunch more thoughts about life and the pursuit of happiness (which is another interesting thought).</p>

<p>I can see this blog page becoming a conversation with myself that other people can read and laugh at or take things from. If you want to talk about it- reach out to me! These posts are really great ways for me to be reflective and develop insight into my own life- which often becomes crazy.</p>

<p>Also there are approximately 5 people who read this now. Kind of a neat community. I appreciate y’all reading when you can. This is much more for myself than for anyone else- but that was my goal with this. This will be a collection of my thoughts, ideas, experiences, etc. I am so excited to be doing this. Feel free to share as you want- I do not mind who reads it.</p>

<p>PSA
I love frogs and have never actually eaten a real one.</p>

<p>Thanks
Mom.</p>

<p>Jackson Miskill</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eating Frogs jmiskill]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/07/Reflections.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflections" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/07/Reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/07/Reflections.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="reflections">Reflections</h1>
<p>jmiskill</p>

<p>January 7, 2023</p>

<p>I recently followed a man on LinkedIn who posts advice and musings that I find to be actually interesting and maybe even a little helpful. His name is Sahil Bloom. On LinkedIn, he posted three questions that I wanted to use to reflect. I am a strong proponent of constant reflection. Today I am going to answer his three questions.</p>

<p>What really matters in my life right now? Am I dedicating the necessary energy to it?
The biggest thing that matters in my life right now is my health. To you, the reader, this may seem shallow, but I assure you it is something that is a journey and process that yields far more than simply doing a few push ups and going for a run.</p>

<p>A quick background on my history with health:</p>

<p>Young:</p>

<p>My interest in health started as a child nearing “teenagedom”. My mom always stressed to me the importance of health, saying things along the lines of, “Health is the number one priority. Everything else comes after that.”</p>

<p>I grew up playing soccer and as a result I was constantly running (and fit). My dad used to be my coach and would make my team and I run shuttle sprints (called something a bit different back then) and do a few dozen push ups before we were allowed to have a full scrimmage. As I write, I am realizing that this is my first memory of loving exercise.</p>

<p>When I got to middle school, I was a bit of floater – trying to figure out where I fit in socially. As I bounced around different social groups and dealing with a big trauma, I grew to be relatively unfit in comparison to my peers, which was something that surprised me given that I played soccer. I got cut from the middle school soccer team, twice, and played club ball where I was benched more than I was played. It was also the time where I started to feel knee injuries and experiment with the sport. Plain and simple: I just was not skillful enough or healthy enough, both physically and mentally.</p>

<p>High School</p>

<p>Once I got to high school, I tried out a sport that a friend of mine suggested: rowing. I absolutely fell in love with it. I was highly competitive and I became incredibly fit. In my freshman year, I lifted for the first time, competed and did well in rowing competitions, and took 2nd at a state competition in a 4-man boat. I felt alive. I was thriving. In sophomore year, I got even better, rowing with the varsity crew team. I got a lot faster, a lot better, and a lot more fit. At the end of the season, I took 2nd place in a quad full of seniors and 10th at a regatta where we normally got 30th. I was on top of the world. Things changed very quickly for me, however, as in my junior year, I stopped rowing. I was having serious mental health issues and needed to step away. Unfortunately, I did not go back. Instead, I played soccer again- the sport I missed dearly. I captained the mens soccer team in my junior and senior year seasons (the sport was in the Spring). I felt very lost during this time- like I had little to no purpose. Coming from crew, I really had no path to follow.</p>

<p>the 10th place boat I was a part of.
COVID-19 and College</p>

<p>Then, COVID-19 happened and I was forced to adopted the individualist approach to exercise. Every day of quarantine I would go for a run and do calisthenic exercises and I became fit again. I felt like my old crew self was coming back again!</p>

<p>Then, college happened. In my first semester, I started lifting weights per the encouragement and excitement from my hall-mates (and future roommates). I did this for a semester on a great routine that really manifested goodness within me. I still felt good and productive. Very much like myself, again.</p>

<p>Then, I rushed and stopped working out on a routine basis because I was so busy. Since then, I lost touch with the routine that I had developed at crew and my first semester of college. I would run occasionally and lift occasionally. I felt like I was way too busy to do anything. For months I was on a consistently downward trajectory. Every week felt worse than the last. All as a result of dealing with some mental hardships. Then, as a cherry on top, in Spring 2022 I tore my ACL. I had surgery May 17th, 2022 and have been in physical therapy since then. It was almost poetic.</p>

<p>Now</p>

<p>I have recently gotten back into a better routine of working out and have developed what I believe to be a great system for me to work out. I lift every other day and go for a run on the days in between those. I am working on building that routine again!</p>

<p>Let’s Talk About All of That</p>

<p>A lot has happened in my health journey. This journey was much more than just what sorts of exercises I was doing and what sport I was playing. Over the course of these early years, I redefined what it meant for me to be healthy. And I am still working on it.</p>

<p>My Definition</p>

<p>To be absolutely clear, it took me a long time to come to this point of thinking. This view, this ideal for myself. Moreover, it took me a long time to convince myself that this view was good for me and should be the number one thing I put before everything else.</p>

<p>For me, health is about being physically strong, mentally awake, and morally straight. This is taken from the Boy Scout oath (as I was a scout from ages 7-18). Quitting rowing was a pivotal moment for me. I was quitting because I was so anxious that I could not think straight (hence not mentally awake). I felt like I was not morally straight either as I felt I was losing the capacity to care for people in the way I had when I was much younger. This was crushing.</p>

<p>There is a lot to unpack with this. My views are still shaky and I believe that this is something that needs to be dealt with on a long term basis, which is why I will be dedicating a post a week to speaking about health and my journey with it. I am only an expert on myself. Only on me. But I want to discuss the things that have impacted my journey with health.</p>

<p>For now, it is enough to answer the question. What really matters in my life right now is health. I want to be the best at being physically strong (fitness), mentally awake(mental health and feeling awake), and morally straight (doing the Right things that are Good for me). Am I dedicating the necessary energy to it? Yes. But I am not perfect. Every day, I get 1% better. By the end of the year I will be 365% better than when I started.</p>

<p>Are my current systems and habits aligned with my long term goals?
Routine is my best friend, but I have not been good in return. Some of my best, most productive, happy moments in life were the moments where I had a solid, established routine. Take sophomore year for example. I would get up and go to school at 7:00 every day, would sit through 4, 90 minute classes with 1, 30 minute lunch and then go to crew where I would part-take in several different exercises where I was routinely getting better every day. Every day I learned, created, solved, and became stronger. It was perfect.</p>

<p>There were two points in my life that I made routine my enemy: junior year of high school when I quit crew and my second year + third year first semester of college (which, at the time of writing this, was this past semester). I lost my way. I would wake up and fight through every day rather than flying like I did during crew.</p>

<p>The Routine</p>

<p>Read (30 min)
Work-out (1 hour)
Meditate (15 minutes)
Personal Code (30 minutes – 1 hour)
Practice Music (30 minutes – 1 hour)
I recognize that this is a lot, but these are aspects of my life that I routinely neglect during school semesters. Even if I only get to 30 minutes of the practice things every day, I will sleep soundly as I will know I held the instrument and played (and consequently got better) and wrote code (and consequently got better).</p>

<p>A slight side note</p>

<p>My big thing is that I need to do things physically in order to understand how they work and to get better at them. This is why I have the meditation, music, and coding built into my routine. I need to practice and don’t have much time to do so. The tough thing is that I will be dedicating roughly 4 hours of my day, every day to these things, which will be incredibly difficult with classes and needing to study and Phi Delt and Philanthropy and all of that. But, I believe that I can do it and get 8 hours of sleep. I just need discipline.</p>

<p>What do I need to cut out of my life to operate more efficiently?
There are three things I want/need to cut out of my life: stall periods, lack of attention/flow, and consumption.</p>

<p>I need to cut out stall periods where I am inactive. I have acquired a bad habit of sitting around sort of waiting for something to happen, when I could be using that time to work on something. This both wastes time and makes it difficult for me to react when I need to get something done. I want to replace these stall periods with reading or studying or practice doing something. That way I don’t need a ton of mental energy but can really put myself into what I am doing.</p>

<p>I have another bad habit of attention. I have a lot of ideas and things that I want to accomplish, and a lot of the time, I will multi-task, when I should just do one thing at a time. Recently, I have bee reading a book on “flow”, which is a psychological phenomenon that human beings experience when they have an “optimal experience”. I was turned onto it by a YouTuber that I watch- John Fish. I want to create optimal flow experience conditions for myself when I am working on things that really matter to me. I believe that I can eradicate this with better focus on the constraints and environment of the task and attention to the task itself.</p>

<p>YouTube and consumption rather than creation. I am super super bad about using YouTube for consumption purposes rather than creation and learning. I will sit there and watch endless “funny video reels” and video-game walkthroughs because of the nostalgia and ease of mental capacity. This is something I do in “stall moments”. I think that YouTube is a beautiful thing, but that I use it incredibly wrong in a lot of ways. Further than this is the juxtaposition of consumption rather than creation. Creation is a beautiful, complex phenomenon. We as human being ogle at it. However, we have been seduced into being consumption-oriented creatures as opposed to creation oriented creatures. I want to be someone who creates things rather than consumes them. Hence: this blog.</p>

<p>Fin
I have had a great time answering these questions. This post has helped me to organize myself in a way that is different and better than before. I hope whoever reads this finds inspiration despite only being able to consume the writing. Further, I sincerely hope you use the questions and ideas to write (create) on your own.</p>

<p>Further, I expect some of my articles to be this long, but some to be much shorter. I have many thoughts and I want to get them written down!</p>

<p>jackson miskill</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections jmiskill]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beginning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/04/The-Beginning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beginning" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/04/The-Beginning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/04/The-Beginning.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-beginning">The beginning</h1>
<p>jmiskill</p>

<p>January 4, 2023</p>

<p>Welcome to the weirdest thing you will probably ever read.</p>

<p>This is a journal of my life. Inspired by my grandma, I thought it would be a brilliant idea to document various aspects of my life in a more persistent manner than simply writing my thoughts down in a physical journal.</p>

<p>You see, I have actually been keeping a journal for quite some time now, but I have not been incredibly consistent about actually following through with the journal itself. So, I wanted to start this blog/journal in order to keep consistency and to allow my family member from across the country to read through some of the crazy things going on in my life.</p>

<p>What will be going on:
To be clear, I will not be writing about the incredibly intimate details of my life (like how I go to town on Taco Bell value menu burritos with my little brother), but rather include events I go to, thoughts I have, and things I am working on.</p>

<p>I will write a post once a week. The following things will be covered.</p>

<p>Computer Science and or Cognitive Science
An event going on/ that has already happened in my life
Thoughts that I have been having
Things I have been working on (both physical projects as well as mental/emotional aspirations).
I will include pictures and will write in a conversational-style.</p>

<p>This is the first time I am publishing something like this to the Internet. Furthermore, I am considering this website a long term project that will hopefully continue well into the future! As I figure out what I want to post and don’t want to post, I expect this blog to evolve into what is essentially a virtual version of me.</p>

<p class="css/">Thank you for reading.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The beginning jmiskill]]></summary></entry></feed>